<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:56583</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:07:11Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>driver</setSpec>
    <setSpec>D60000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">NIPO weekpeilingen 1982</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:parTitl xml:lang="en">NIPO opinion polls 1982</ddi:parTitl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:56583</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-z4s-be79</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">Netherlands Institute for Public Opinion and Marketing Research - NIPO</ddi:AuthEnty>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2014-01-15"/>
         </ddi:distStmt>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">publieke opinie onderzoek</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">opinion poll</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Social sciences</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">Data derived from weekly public opinion polls in the Netherlands in 1982 concerning social and political issues. Samples were drawn from the Dutch population aged 18 years and older.

All data from the surveys held between 1962 and 2000 are available in the DANS data collections.

Background variables 1982: 
Sex / age / religion / income / vote recall latest elections / party preference / level of education / union membership / professional status / &lt; self > left‐right rating / party alignment / province / degree of urbanization / weight factor.

Topical variables:
n8201: Wage control expected income this year / Income less or higher than last year / Satisfaction with income / Making ends meet / Respondent's opinion on government's wage control / Confidence in Van Agt, Den Uyl, Terlouw, Wiegel / Respondents' opinion on present government.
n8202: Profit rate, Poland, war profit rate at company where respondent is working / Profit rate of most of Dutch industry too high or too low / Respondent agrees with contention profit rate of most companies is too low / Should Polish trade- union Solidarity resist or obey Polish government / Military counterbalance needed in West-Europe against USSR and East-Europe / Should Holland stay in NATO or get out / In case of total war should Holland defend itself or rather surrender / Accept a Russian occupation or defend itself at all risks / Respondent's estimate of own chances of survival in case of war in Europe.
n8203: Confidence in Labour Party / Changes in sick benefit / Sickness during last winter / How many days respondent could not work because he was ill / Sick days were paid / Holland and other European countries should take measures against USSR and Poland / Should Polish trade union solidarity continue its resistance or stop all action / Respondent heard or read about government plans to reduce sick pay to 80 percent of salary / Should these plans be carried out / Would respondent participate in actions like strikes against these cuts in sick benefit / Confidence in Van Agt, Terlouw, Wiegel, Labour Party.
n8205: Labour Party / If member of Labour Party would respondent leave this party now / If new Labour Party would be founded would respondent vote for it.
n8206: Confidence in labour politicians / Did anything happen which changed respondents' opinion on CDA, D66, VVD, PvdA / Changes in opinion on PvdA by the stand taken by PvdA administration / Cuts in sick benefit / Employment plan of Den Uyl / The stand of PvdA on nuclear energy / Confidence in Den Uyl, Van der Louw, Van Dam / Respondent expects plans on cuts in sick benefit will be carried out / Respondent expects social insurance payments will continue to be indexed to minimum wage / Importance of work in respondents' life.
n8207: Awareness coming elections / next leader PvdA / Respondent knows when next elections will be / These will be national, provincial or local elections / Respondent will go and vote next provincial elections, March 24th / Respondent is sure which party he will vote for / Which parties should leave present coalition of CDA, PvdA and D66 / Should other party get in government Van Agt / Who will be next leader of PvdA / Clearness of present position of PvdA, D66, CDA, VVD / Confidence in president Reagan.
n8208: Confidence in Van Agt, Terlouw, Den Uyl, Wiegel / Where will Spain end on the list at world championship soccer / Respondent likes soccer.
n8209: Provincial elections / Profit rate / Constitution / Will respondent go and vote next provincial elections / Which party will he vote for / Profit rate at company where respondent works / Profit rate in most of Dutch industry too low or too high / Profit making is absolutely necessary or not allowed / What is a fair net profit in terms of percentage from selling prices / Should managers, designers etc. earn a lot / Respondent agrees or disagrees with article 7 of Dutch constitution referring to freedom of the press / Respondent agrees or disagrees with other articles of Dutch constitution.
n8211: Provincial elections / Plan for creating jobs / Changes in sick pay / Will respondent go and vote next provincial elections / Which party will he vote for / Profit rate at company where respondent is working / How many jobs will be created according to plan Den Uyl / Respondent knows what this plan will cost / Respondent thinks it is right to raise taxes for financing plan Den Uyl / Will this plan succeed in reducing unemployment / Will respondent himself or someone in family benefit from this plan / Did respondent join strike for plans to change sick benefit / Changes in sick benefit will be detrimental for himself / Is there someone seriously disabled within family, relatives, friends / Would respondent be prepared to pay 1 percent more in transport costs in favour of seriously disabled persons.
n8212: Provincial elections / Taxes / Which political parties will lose or win a lot next provincial elections / What makes respondent think so friends or forecasts / Should new government be formed after next provincial elections / Should there be parliamentary by-elections / Which political parties should form coalition / who for prime-minister / Respondent is obliged to return a declaration for Income tax / Respondent is paying property-tax / Respondent is able to write declaration himself or needs help / Problem with Income tax / Treatment by collector.
n8213: Profit rate / Profit sharing / Sick benefit / Profit rate of company where respondent is working / Respondent shares in profit / Profit rate of most of Dutch industry too low or too high / Freeze of salaries during three years to promote profit rate / Respondent could make ends meet with same salary during three years / If workers would share in profit would respondent agree with freeze in salary / Will profit sharing promote better work / Respondent could achieve more in same working day / Does it happen that people say they are sick while actually they could work / Respondent agrees with no sick benefit during first day and complete pay afterwards.
n8214: Provincial elections / Respondent watched provincial elections on TV / Respondent satisfied with results / Should new coalition be formed / Should PvdA leave government Van Agt.
n8215: Provincial elections / Emigration / Respondent did vote last provincial elections / Respondent did vote former elections / Should compulsory voting be reestablished / Voting does matter for what happens in country / Does it matter which party one votes for / Respondent prefers to stay in Holland or wants to emigrate / Emigrate to what country.
n8216: Opinion on present government / Expectations of political issues / Respondent's opinion on present government / Should this government stay or leave / Will this government last this year / Confidence in Van Agt, Den Uyl, Terlouw, Wiegel, Van der Louw, Van Dam / Welfare benefits will stay the same or be reduced / Will there be sufficient cuts in public expenditures / Existing nuclear plants stay open or be closed down / New nuclear arms will be placed in Holland too / Wage control or wages will be left to unions and employers / How much politicians can do for good of country.
n8217: Government's note of this spring / Labour Party / Falklands / Respondent heard or read about government's note / Respondents' opinion on this note / Sufficient cuts in public expenditures / Raise of social premiums too high or too low / Den Uyl should he have resigned or stayed / Should other PvdA ministers have resigned or stayed / PvdA is following a clear policy at this moment / Should Argentina leave the Falklands / Should England dislodge Argentina even by force / Should Falkland Islands stay British or belong to Argentina.
n8218: Visit queen to United States / Confidence in Dutch political parties / Falklands / Wiegel / Respondent followed news on queen's visit to USA / Visit useful / reception of queen in USA / USA is Holland's best friend, business relation or enemy / Confidence in Reagan / Confidence USA in Holland / Confidence in Dutch political parties / Respondent followed news on Falkland crisis / Should Argentina leave Falkland Islands / Should Argentina be dislodged from Falkland Islands by British attack / Respondent agrees with economic sanctions of Holland against Argentina / What should Holland do in case of foreign occupation of Curaçao, Aruba / Measures should be taken now to protect Curaçao, Aruba by Dutch navy / Respondent heard about Wiegel's appointment as a governor of Friesland / This appointment is favourable for VVD, for Holland / Respondent heard about Nijpels as new leader of VVD / Confidence in Nijpels.
n8219: Awareness coming local elections, June 2nd. / Respondent knows when next elections will be / Kind of elections / Will respondent go and vote for local elections, June 2nd. / Choice influenced by local policy or by national policy of particular party / Interested in local, provincial or national, political issues.
n8220: Ability to do sums.
n8221: Making ends meet / Most urgent tasks new government / Respondent can make ends meet / Situation last year / Respondent considers his family as prosperous / Future will be better or worse financially / Respondents' income above or under real minimum wage level / How many persons in family have no income of their own / How many persons in family are wage earners / Most urgent tasks for new government to do / Respondent read or heard about trouble in PvdA / Den Uyl or Van den Berg is right / If PvdA should change policy in what direction.
n8222: Crisis in government / Confidence in politicians / PvdA ministers were right to leave government / Should PvdA ministers be in new government again / Should Den Uyl become minister again / Should Van Agt become prime-minister again / Which political parties should form new government now / Confidence in Van Agt, Terlouw, Den Uyl, Wiegel, Nijpels, Van Dam, Van der Louw, Lubbers.
n8224: National economic situation / Political leaders / Respondent expects growth, stagnation or recession of Dutch economy / Measures of new government could make economic growth possible / Government's measures, introduction of part-time jobs, general cut in income, lower costs for Dutch industry, trade union activities can reduce unemployment / Welfare facilities influenced reduction of unemployment / Should Van Agt be leader of CDA again next nation elections / Should Den Uyl be leader of PvdA again / Should Terlouw be leader of D66 again / Should Nijpels be leader of VVD.
n8225: Voting / New government / Confidence in politicians / Respondent did vote last elections and former elections / Voting influence what happens in country / Which party one votes for does matter / Importance of next national elections / Respondent will vote next national elections, September 8th / Respondent is sure which party he will vote for / Should D66 stay in new government if VVD gets in and PvdA gets out / Should PvdA be in new government together with CDA again / Should VVD be in new government / Confidence in Nijpels, Den Uyl, Van Agt, Terlouw.
n8226: National elections, September 8th / TV / Respondent knows date of next elections / Respondent knows what kind of elections / Respondent will vote next elections / Respondent sure which party he will vote for / Should CDA and VVD together get a majority / Respondents' preference for prominent political persons / TV set in respondents' living room / TV in bedroom / TV in other room / Respondent would cooperate in NIPO survey on TV.
n8227: PvdA ministers / New government / Confidence in politics / PvdA ministers were right to leave government / Should PvdA ministers get in new government / Should Den Uyl be minister again, should Van Agt be prime-minister again / Which political parties should form new government now / Terlouw, Den Uyl, Wiegel, Nijpels, Van Dam, Van der Louw, Lubbers.
n8228: Things go in right, wrong direction in Holland regarding in general / Reduction of inflation / Growth of unemployment / Cost of living / Labour management relations / Relations between labour and government / Fuel and energy supply / Quality of consumer goods / Social relations in plant / Ecology / Quality of education / Quality of public transport / Safety in the streets / Financial security when aged / Discipline and tidiness of our people / Welfare facilities in Holland / Housing / Respondent's income / Respondent's future / Respondent will go and vote next national elections / Respondent sure which party to vote for / clearness of policy of CDA, D66, VVD, PvdA.
n8229: Next national elections, September 8th / Respondent will go and vote next national elections / Which party respondent will vote for / Respondent sure about this choice / Respondents' second choice / Respondents' educational level.
n8230: National elections / Visiting Dutch beaches / Respondent will go and vote next national elections, September 8th / Which party respondent will vote for / Respondent sure about this choice / Respondents' second choice / Respondent visited the beach this year / By which means of transport / Which clothes at the beach / Respondent ever visited islands such as Texel, Terschelling / Respondent ever visited South-Limburg, Amsterdam, The Hague, Rotterdam, Veluwe, Achterhoek, Twente, Friesland, Groningen.
n8231: National elections / Confidence in political parties, politicians / New coalition / Domestic affairs / Fear of war / Educational level / Respondent will go and vote next national elections / Which party respondent will vote for / Respondent sure about this choice / Respondents' second choice / Respondents' confidence in Van Agt, Terlouw, Den Uyl, Nijpels / Respondent's opinion on what should be done with respect to pollution of environment / Strengthening the position of Dutch industry / Public expenditures / Lower incomes and welfare payments / Nuclear plants / Safety in the streets / Placing new nuclear arms / Shorter working hours and reduction of salary for employment ends / The cost of health care / Freezing all incomes / Probability of war in West-Europe within next five years / Attained educational level of respondent.
n8232: National elections / Retrenchment policy by what party / Respondent will vote next national elections / Which party respondent will vote for / Respondent sure about this choice / Respondents' second choice / Respondent did vote on former occasions / Respondent always voted for same political party or frequently changed sides / Which parties will win or lose next elections / Which political party is best suited for carrying through an unpleasant retrenchment policy / Which politician is best suited for this task.
n8233: National elections / New coalition / Who for prime minister / New nuclear arms / Confidence in politicians, politics / Cuts in wages / Making ends meet / Respondent will go and vote next national elections / Which party respondent will vote for / Respondent sure about this choice / Respondents' second choice / Respondent did vote on former occasions / Respondent always voted for same political party or frequently changed sides / If possible for whom respondent would vote as prime minister / Should new government take a clear stand on placement of new nuclear arms / Confidence in Van Agt, Terlouw, Den Uyl, Nijpels, politics in The Hague / Respondent could live on a 10 , 7 1/2 , 5 , 2 1/2 , 1 percent cut in increase.
n8234: National elections / Domestic politics / Strengthening police force / Taxes / Respondent will vote next national elections / Which party respondent will vote for / Respondent sure about this choice / Respondents' second choice / Respondent did vote on former occasions / Respondent always voted for same party or frequently changed sides / If possible for whom respondent would vote as prime minister / Should new government be clear on placement of new nuclear arms / CDA, D66, VVD, PvdA, have a clear policy / Government should be more active on fight against pollution of environment / Road construction / Strengthening of police force / Hospitals / Respondent prepared to pay Hfl. 1 extra tax per for environment / Road construction / Strengthening of police force / Hospitals.
n8235: National elections / Vote recommendation of IKV / Respondent will go and vote next national elections / Which party respondent will vote for / Respondent sure about this choice / Respondents' second choice / Respondent did vote on former occasions / Respondent always voted for same party or frequently changed sides / Respondent heard or read about recommendation of IKV to vote for parties opposed to placement of new nuclear arms / Respondent knows which parties one should not vote for according to IKV / Respondent cares about this recommendation / Respondent thinks it is right for religious organizations to do so / Respondent's opinion on in- dependent voting behaviour of members of parliament.
n8236: National elections / Vote recommendation of IKV / Retrenchment policy of next government / Respondent will go and vote next national elections / Which party respondent will vote for / respondent sure about this choice / Respondents' second choice / Respondent did vote on former occasions / Respondent always voted for same party or frequently changed sided / Respondent heard or read about recommendation of IKV to vote for parties opposed to placement of new nuclear arms / Respondent cares about this recommendation / Respondent's opinion on plans to reduce income tax and to raise vat / To abolish automatic price compensation / To abolish minimum wages for youth / To abolish minimum wage for everyone / To reduce unemployment benefits from 80 to 70 percent of last wage.
n8237: National elections / Parties to form next government / Respondent watched the poll results on TV last / Which party won according to respondent which parties should form new government now / Respondent did go and vote himself / Respondent only voted for himself or also for someone else / Did someone else vote for respondent / Which party respondent voted for last week.
n8238: Parties to form new government / Who for prime minister / Within how many weeks should formation be ready / Which parties should form new government / Who should be prime minister / Respondent expects who will be prime minister / Which parties will form new government.
n8239: Government budget plans 1983 / Parties to form new government / Who for prime minister / Government budget plans clear for respondent / Respondent personally will benefit or not from government plans / Plan right or wrong / reduction in public expenditures will be sufficient / New government should carry out or change plans / Which parties should form new government / Who should be prime minister / Who will be prime minister / Which parties will form new government.
n8240: Formation of new government / Retrenchment policy / Opposition to retrenchment policy / Middle East / Dutch soldiers in Lebanon / Respondent interested in news about formation of new government / Importance of having new government soon / Necessity of retrenchment policy / Should one support this policy or oppose it / Strikes will be effective against retrenchment policy or plans will be carried out anyway / Respondent sympathizes with Israel / Respondent sympathizes with Palestinians / Dutch soldiers should stay in Lebanon or come back.
n8241: New government / Opposition of PvdA / Political leaders / Plans for tax reforms / Respondent’s confidence in new government / PvdA should pursue vigorous opposition policy / Den Uyl should stay as leader of PvdA / Most suited successor of Den Uyl / Should Terlouw stay as leader of D66 / Most suited successor of Terlouw / Respondent would benefit from 5 percent less wage tax and income tax and a raise of vat / 1 percent raise of vat and 10 percent less wage and income tax / 1 percent raise of vat and 15 percent less wage tax and income tax / Opinion on strong reductions in wage tax and income tax / Respondents' opinion an strong reductions in wage tax and income tax and a raise of vat from 18 to 19 percent.
n8243: Confidence in politicians / Police against rioting / At former elections respondent voted for same party or frequently changed sides / Respondent's confidence in new government / Lubbers / Den Uyl / Nijpels / Respondent's opinion on police actions against riots in Amsterdam / Should there more teargas be used on such occasions / If necessary, should police use firearms / respondent knows names of new commodities.
n8245: Confidence in new government / Opposition to new government / Drugs / At former elections respondent voted for same party or frequently changed sides / Confidence in new government / Respondents' opinion on plans of new government for tax reform / Income policy / Respondents' opinion on strikes against government plans / Respondent will strike himself / Respondent ever tried soft drugs / Use of soft drugs will change to use of hard drugs / Soft drugs, cigarettes, hard drugs, alcohol should be legalized / When respondent goes on holiday he leaves the house empty or someone else moves in / When empty respondent turns off gas main, water and electricity.
n8246: Confidence in new government, politicians / At former occasions respondent always voted for same party or frequently changed sides / Confidence in new government / Respondent's opinion on tax plans of new government / Respondent's opinion on plans for income policy of new government / Confidence in Engwirda, Nijpels, Lubbers, Den Uyl, Wiegel, Van Agt.
n8247: Railway and teachers strikes / Confidence in new government / Crime / Sinterklaas 1982 / At former elections respondent always voted for same party or frequently changed sides / Respondent heard or read about railway and teachers strikes before / Is it justified for railway men to strike / Is it justified for teachers to strike / If respondent was railway man or teacher, would he strike himself / Railway strike caused trouble to respondent himself / Respondent noticed something of teachers' strike / Government has the right to fire civil servants on strike according to respondent / Confidence in new government / Respondent expects from new government sufficient cuts in public expenditures / Does respondent ever feels insecure and where / Respondent will give presents, write rhymes, make surprise packets at Sinterklaas / Respondent will spend more or less money on Sinterklaas than last year.
n8248: Countries more prosperous than Holland / Christmas / Quality of tap water / At former elections respondent always voted for same party or frequently changed sides / What will respondent do during Christmas, New Years Eve.
n8249: Shorter working hours / Air pollution and water pollution / Fireworks on new years eve / At former elections respondent always voted for same party or frequently changed sides / Respondent heard or read about plans for a gradual shortening of working hours with less pay / Respondents' opinion on this plan / How many hours a respondent is working / Respondent could finish his job in less hours a / If in less hours, how many / Respondent would like to work less himself / Respondent prefers shorter working hours for less pay or more working hours for more pay / Respondent was troubled personally by air pollution and water pollution / Respondent will let off fireworks on New years eve / Will there be a lot of fireworks in neighbourhood / Fireworks annoy respondent / Letting off fireworks should be forbidden.
n8250: At former elections respondent always voted for same party or frequently changed sides.
n8251: Strikes of civil servants / A house for oneself / Which payments and subsidies could be reduced / At former elections respondent always voted for same party or frequently changed sides / Respondent is pro or contra strikes of civil servants / Strikes of civil servants are legal according to respondent / To strike should be allowed for policemen / Railway men / Public transport workers / Firemen / Workers in electricity plants / Hospital workers / Postal clerks / Clerks / Strikes will be effective or retrenchment policy and cuts in wages will be carried out anyhow / From what age young people, leaving school without finding a job, have a right to complete unemployment benefits / From what age one should have a right to a house for oneself / One could reduce unemployment benefits / o.a. p. / Subsidies for house rent / Pensions for the disabled / Subsidies for sport and art / Student grants / Social welfare payments / Everybody has a right to a fair minimum income or a healthy person should look after himself according to respondent.</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr>
            <ddi:nation abbr="NLD" xml:lang="en">The Netherlands</ddi:nation>
            <ddi:collDate event="single">1982</ddi:collDate>
         </ddi:sumDscr>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">OPEN_ACCESS_FOR_REGISTERED_USERS</ddi:restrctn>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: https://dans.knaw.nl/en/about/organisation-and-policy/legal-information/DANSLicence.pdf</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="nl"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>