<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:130499</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:08:00Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>D50000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>D60000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">Generations and Gender Survey (GGS) - Wave 1</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-z5z-xn8g</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:130499</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">Generations and Gender Programme</ddi:AuthEnty>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt/>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">Fertility, family life, complex families, gender relations, work-life balance, children, child-care, transition to adulthood, relationship, partnership, marriage, separation, divorce, parenthood, generation, older ages, attitudes, well-being, employment, poverty, retirement, 2000s, survey data, Europe, Japan, Australia, cross-national, longitudinal, individual-level.</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Social sciences</ddi:topcClas>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Behavioural and educational sciences</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">The Generations and Gender Survey (GGS) is an individual-level survey which aims to improve understanding of family life, such as partnership formation and dissolution, fertility and intergenerational solidarity. The GGS provides detailed information on: household composition, biological and non-biological children, current and previous partnerships, household organisation and task division, parents and parental home, pregnancy and fecundity, health and well-being, individual's and partner's activity status and income, earnings assets and transfers, and value orientations and attitudes. The GGS has as a panel design, collecting information on the same persons at three-year intervals. Data processing included central harmonization of the national datasets. Data was collected among men and women between the ages of 18 and 80. GGS Wave 1 was fielded in 19 countries (Australia, Austria, Belgium, Bulgaria, Czech Republic, Estonia, France, Georgia, Germany, Hungary, Italy, Japan, Lithuania, Netherlands, Norway, Poland, Romania, Russian Federation, Sweden) in the period from 2004 to 2013. Wave 1 has an average of 9,000 respondents per country. Individual-level data access is provided via www.ggp-i.org.</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr/>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">NO_ACCESS</ddi:restrctn>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="en"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>