<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:38485</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:06:42Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>D50000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">Using Interactive Features to Motivate and Probe Responses to Open-Ended Questions (LISS Core Study)</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:38485</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-zsp-agty</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">CentERdata - Institute for data collection and research - Tilburg University</ddi:AuthEnty>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2010-05-28"/>
         </ddi:distStmt>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">response behavior</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">web survey</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">probes</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">open-ended question</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Behavioural and educational sciences</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">The project explores how interactive features in web surveys can influence respondent behavior.         
In August 2008, the LISS panel was presented a questionnaire on the effect of including motivational statements and follow-up probes on response length and response quality of the responses to open-ended questions. The questionnaire included four open-ended questions and several closed-ended questions about the current situation in Dutch society. Respondents to the internet survey were randomly assigned to one of the four versions of the open-ended questions. The control version simply displayed the open-ended question; no motivating statement was included with the question and respondents were not branched to a follow-up probe. In the second version the open-ended question included the motivational statement ‘This question is very important to our survey’, but similar to the control version, respondents were not asked a follow-up probe. In the third version respondents were asked the open-ended question and after they submitted their initial response, they were branched to a follow-up probe screen. This screen displayed the respondent’s answer to the initial open-ended question and a follow-up probe (e.g., ‘Is there anything else you would like to add?’). Respondents to the fourth version were also asked the initial open-ended question and then branched to a follow-up probe with a motivational statement. In addition, people who did not answer the initial open-ended question (or who provided an answer like ‘don’t know’ or other answers that were less than four characters) were routed to a nonrespondent version that displayed the text ‘Please provide a response. This question is very important to our survey” and repeated the open-ended question.</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr>
            <ddi:collDate event="single">2008</ddi:collDate>
         </ddi:sumDscr>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">NO_ACCESS</ddi:restrctn>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="English"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="Dutch"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="en"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="nl"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>