<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:67379</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:07:34Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>D30000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">Arab West Report 2007, Weeks 04-51: Media Critique, The Question of Conversion, and Muslim-Christian Relations</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-x68-u8kb</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:67379</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en" affiliation="Center for Intercultural Dialogue and Translation (CIDT)">Hulsman, Drs. C.</ddi:AuthEnty>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="contributor" affiliation="Center for Intercultural Dialogue and Translation (CIDT)">Sparks, MA M.R.</ddi:othId>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="contributor" affiliation="Center for Arab West Understanding (CAWU)">Birk, A.S.</ddi:othId>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="contributor" affiliation="Center for Arab West Understanding (CAWU)">Anwar, Dr. S.</ddi:othId>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="contributor" affiliation="Centre for Arab-West Understanding (CAWU)">Gabra Ayoub Khalil, S.</ddi:othId>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="contributor" affiliation="Center for Arab West Understanding (CAWU)">Koehler, K.</ddi:othId>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="contributor" affiliation="Center for Arab-West Understanding (CAWU)">Fastenrath, C.</ddi:othId>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="contributor">Levine, Dr. L.F.</ddi:othId>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="contributor" affiliation="Center for Arab-West Understanding (CAWU)">Muhammad al-Duwīnī, W.</ddi:othId>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="contributor" affiliation="Center for Arab-West Understanding (CAWU)">Rezzonico, M.</ddi:othId>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="contributor" affiliation="Center for Arab-West Understanding (CAWU)">Akselbo Holm, M.</ddi:othId>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="contributor" affiliation="Center for Intercultural Dialogue and Translation (CIDT)">Richards-Benson, S.</ddi:othId>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt/>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">Media Critique</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">The Question of Conversion</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">Muslim-Christian Relations</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Humanities</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">This dataset contains the Arab-West Report special reports that were published in 2007. This dataset mainly contains the writings of Cornelis Hulsman, Drs., among other authors on topics related to Muslim- Christian relations and interfaith dialogue. Additionally, this dataset features certain reports related to the Christian faith in Egypt, Monastic life and Coptic traditions. 

Some of the articles address the media coverage of Muslim-Christian incidents and sectarian tensions, and how biased media reporting can often exacerbate existing tensions between groups. These articles feature a number of interviews conducted by Arab West Report with prominent social figures and scholars. 

Additionally, reports from this dataset discuss conversion cases and interfaith meetings that were held at the time. This dataset also contains media critique from Arab West Report Editor-in-Chief Cornelis Hulsman, Drs.

Some of the themes that characterize this dataset include:

-  Authors report on their trip to see the celebration of the Holy Family crossing the Nile River in a village in Upper Egypt. They reflect on their experiences and the need to improve dialogue between Muslims and Christians in Egypt.

- An overview of a forum organized by the Center for Civilizational Studies and Dialogue between Cultures at Cairo University to introduce a book written by Father Christian van Nispen, sj,  entitled, ‘Christians and Muslims: Brothers before God.’ van Nispen’s principle argument is that both Muslims and Christians worship one and the same God, but according to different understandings. 

- Another report highlighted the second conference on bias, entitled: ‘The International Conference for Dialogue between Civilizations and the Different Tracks of Knowledge.’ The 4-day conference, was sponsored by the Program for Civilizational Studies and Dialogue between Cultures at Cairo University, and the International Institute of Islamic Thought.

- The Arab West Report annual report: The Center for Arab-West Understanding presents its annual report for 2006.

Media critique:

- “Minister Of Awqaf Dr. Hamdi Zakzouk Falsely Accused Of Calling For The Death Penalty For Apostates From Islam”: Arab-West Report responds to media claims that Dr. Hamdi Zakzouk called for the death penalty for apostates from Islam.

-In another report, the authors stress that misguided media reporting often only serves to further tensions, particularly in cases of sectarian strife.  Another article presents the transcript of a lecture for the Arab Thought Forum. It considers media distortions and mis-representation in the media that only serve to further antagonize Muslim-Christian relations and the perception of Islam / the Arab world in the West. Cornelis Hulsman, Drs., explains the role of the Center for Arab West Understanding, and the importance of constructive, unbiased, and fully researched journalism.

-Hulsman stressed in one of his articles that media frequently manipulate headlines in an effort to present stories in the context they desire. Headlines are also frequently sensationalized in an effort to attract a larger number of readers, but if this also distorts a story this should be questioned. Cornelis Hulsman, Drs., stresses the danger of ignorant media reporting, and the damage that inaccurate fact-checking can cause. He provides a number of examples from various intellectuals, commenting on stories that have been sensationalized in the media, and the negative effects this reporting had on Arab-West relations and on furthering dialogue between the Islamic and Arab world and the West. 

Interviews:

-“An interview With Father Basilius About Father Matta Al-Maskin”: Father Basilius discusses the history and theological philosophies of Father Mattá al-Maskīn. The interview is mainly focused on theology and the practices of clergymen.

-  An interview with Tarek Heggy at CIDT where Drs. Cornelis Hulsman and staff members discuss sensitive issues throughout the Arab world.

- An interview by AWR/ CIDT interns with Dr. Hala Mustafa, where she comments on her role in the National Democratic Party’s Policies Committee, her opinions on reform in Egypt, critiques the role of Egyptian security, and outlines the necessary steps needed for reform to take effect.

- “Saad Eddin Ibrahim Meets With CIDT Interns To Discuss How Islamists Have Changed”: Saad Eddin Ibrahim, is one of the most outspoken critics of the Egyptian government, who was imprisoned from 2000-2003 for his critique. Saad Eddin Ibrahim is a liberal secularist, but as a result of his strong democratic stance, he defends the rights of all groups in society, including Islamists, to participate in the politics of the country. CIDT-interns met with him for a talk about his life and his views.

-A review of the Annual Anglican-Al Azhar Interfaith Meeting Dialogue held in All-Saints Cathedral which implicitly dealt with dialogue and means of furthering it.

-A report on church response to poverty in Egypt and specifically how this issue is being addressed by the Coptic Orthodox Church in an attempt to alleviate the suffering of Egyptians.

-The following presents an investigative report authored by Mads Akselbo Holm, an intern for Arab-West Report, on the issue of Muslims leaving their faith. This study provides an excellent background to the commotion caused by Muḥammad Ḥijāzī announcing his conversion to Christianity. In addition to that, another article discussed “The Freedom to Change One’s Religion Or Belief”; and another spoke of “Article 18 Of The Universal Declaration Of Human Rights”, indicating that although Egyptian civil law does not prohibit conversion from one religion to another, there are discrepancies in an individual’s ability to convert.

-Debates about freedom of religion and conversion in Egypt focusing on legal cases of conversions, specifically changing one’s religious identity on identification cards.

- A report by Hulsman discussed the state of past and present relations between Muslims and Christians in Egypt. The paper opens by giving information about Pope Shenouda III and the most important incidents that have taken place during his reign. The second half of the paper then looks at specific examples of Christian contributions to Christian-Muslim tensions in contemporary Egypt. 

- An article discusses the exaggerated interpretations of some Western Christians about the position of Christians in Egypt.

Authors featured in this dataset are: 

Cornelis Hulsman, Drs.,  Ane Skov Birk, Salmā Ānwar, Drs. Sawsan Jabrah Ayyub Khalil, Katrin Koehler, Christian Fastenrath, Dr. Larry F. Levine, Wisām Muhammad al-Duwīnī, Maria Rezzonico, Mads Akselbo Holm, and Susan Richards-Benson</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr>
            <ddi:collDate event="single">2007</ddi:collDate>
         </ddi:sumDscr>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">REQUEST_PERMISSION</ddi:restrctn>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: https://dans.knaw.nl/en/about/organisation-and-policy/legal-information/DANSLicence.pdf</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="en"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>