<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:31985</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:05:27Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>D60000:D61000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>driver</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">Aspecten van de levensloop van de Nederlandse bevolking,  2e tranche  1994 : Geschiedenis cultuurparticipatie, taakverdeling  in het huishouden, inkomen, en sociale contacten bij  het vinden van een baan.</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:parTitl xml:lang="en">Aspects of life-event history of the Dutch population,  part 2, history of cultural participation, division of domestic  tasks, income, and use of social contacts in finding a job. 1994</ddi:parTitl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:31985</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-xqx-528b</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">ESR / NWO * Den Haag (primary investigator)</ddi:AuthEnty>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">Stichting Telepanel * Amsterdam (data collector)</ddi:AuthEnty>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="1994-01-01"/>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2007-07-23"/>
         </ddi:distStmt>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">finance</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">gender roles</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">interpersonal relations</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">leisure time</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">work</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">life histories</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">cultural participation</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">employment</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">domestic responsabilities</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">income</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">social networks</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">job hunting</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Sociology</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">P1195a: present cultural activities: spending leisure time / time spent at mentioned activities.

P1195b: past cultural activities: spending leisure time at the age of 15, 21 and 30 / spending leisure time by r.'s parents when r. was 15 years old / possessing domestic appliances and other possessions in and around the house when r. was 15, 21 and 30 years old / number of rooms at r.'s residence.

P1195c: division of domestic tasks: sharing domestic work with partner / having domestic help / sharing domestic tasks in the past by r.'s parents when r. was growing up / sharing tasks with partner concerning caring and upbringing of r.'s children / sharing tasks concerning caring and upbringing, between r.'s parents, when r. was growing up / r'.s opinion about role patterns of partners concerning care for (young) children, working outdoors / working outdoors and/or not working outdoors of r. and partner before and after children were born.

P1195d: income: overview of employment history of respondent (see also P1107) / whether r. had one or more sources of income during periods of unemployment, and if yes which kind of income / overview of r.'s income from r.'s first job through r.'s present job.

P11095e: role of social contacts in getting a job: age at which r. left school / profession of friends and parents / profession of r.'s two best friends (partner excluded), and-or family-members at the age of 35 and at the age of 50 ' profession of r'.s two best friends (partner excluded), and-or family-members at present and whether those two persons know each other / role of relationships (friends, (partner excluded), and-or family members) in changing job(s) / whether r. got his-her first, former, very last, present job via a personal contact and if yes, kind of contact and profession of contact person / most important reason(s) why r. ceased from former, very last job / concerning former, very last, present job: relationship with colleagues with a higher, lower and-or the same function / whether r. knew staff-members rather well before r. applied for present job, function of those staff-members / having applied for a job and being refused, kind of job and how r. came into contact with that vacancy, possible role of a contact person and if yes relationship with that person and his-her profession / contact with friends, relatives, acquaintances having different professional backgrounds.

Background variables: basic characteristics/ housing situation/ household characteristics/ occupation/employment/ education</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr>
            <ddi:collDate event="single">1905 * 1994</ddi:collDate>
         </ddi:sumDscr>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">OPEN_ACCESS_FOR_REGISTERED_USERS</ddi:restrctn>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: https://dans.knaw.nl/en/about/organisation-and-policy/legal-information/DANSLicence.pdf</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>