<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:218883</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-09-13T05:16:29Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>D60000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">Violence against women and the role of economic performance: a study on contemporary Bangladesh</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-x3x-y4ny</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:218883</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en" affiliation="Bangladesh University of Professionals">Sifat, RIDWAN ISLAM</ddi:AuthEnty>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="RightsHolder" affiliation="Bangladesh University of Professionals">Sifat, RIDWAN ISLAM, RightsHolder</ddi:othId>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2021-08-09"/>
         </ddi:distStmt>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">Violence</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">women</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">Bangladesh</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">empowerment</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Social sciences</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">Background: Violence against women has been a consistent phenomenon in all societies, regardless of its demographic characteristics. Especially in a developing country like Bangladesh, where society is going through rapid changes with constant inequality between males and females, this social melancholy is even more severe. Inevitably, violence against any entity is caused by the subordination of that very entity. In a general sense, violence against women can be prevented if women have access to education and are able to participate in economic activity. However, multiple pieces of research abscond this phenomenon by quoting that ‘employment is not empowerment.’ 
Methods: Considering violence against women as one of the severe forms of disempowerment, the authors further extended this concept by using different sets of data to unmask how different types of violence against women are being impacted by the role of economic performance of both men and women. With numerical data from different sources i.e., the World Bank and Ain o Salish Kendro (ASK), the authors have opted for Pearson correlation and ordinary least squared (OLS) methods of regression to unveil the associations followed by magnitudes.
Results: This study finds that the unemployment status of men proportionally affects violence against women (domestic, dowry induced, and rape) and the unemployment status of women is inversely proportional with non-monolithic magnitude in this regard. 
Conclusion: This paper suggests immediate deterrence/ and sufficient change of current policies to empower women. To limit the occurrences of violence against women, re-examining the causal factors are now pivotal. In depth analysis for each type of violence against women is to be done prior to formulating any policy. The authors argue, no one solution can serve efficiently. As such, size in this context and close monitoring is as it is already proven that current policies and practices hardly limits the occurrences of violence against women in Bangladesh.</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr/>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">REQUEST_PERMISSION</ddi:restrctn>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: https://dans.knaw.nl/en/about/organisation-and-policy/legal-information/DANSLicence.pdf</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="en"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>