<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:56761</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:07:13Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>driver</setSpec>
    <setSpec>D60000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">NIPO weekpeilingen 1996</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:parTitl xml:lang="en">NIPO opinion polls 1996</ddi:parTitl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:56761</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-zz4-3hw8</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">Netherlands Institute for Public Opinion and Marketing Research - NIPO</ddi:AuthEnty>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2014-01-21"/>
         </ddi:distStmt>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">publieke opinie onderzoek</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">opinion poll</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Social sciences</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">Data derived from weekly public opinion polls in the Netherlands in 1996 concerning social and political issues. Samples were drawn from the Dutch population aged 18 years and older.

All data from the surveys held between 1962 and 2000 are available in the DANS data collections.

Background variables:
Sex / age / religion / income / vote recall latest elections / party preference / if stated not knowing what party to vote for at next elections: what party will have most chances that respondent will vote for? / level of education / union membership / professional status / &lt; self > left‐right rating / party alignment / province / degree of urbanization / weight factor.

Topical variables:
n9605: If VVD will be largest party after elections, whom from VVD for prime-minister: Bolkestein / Wiegel / Someone else.
n9606: If VVD will be largest party after elections, whom from VVD for prime-minister: Bolkestein / Wiegel / Someone else.
n9607: If VVD will be largest party after elections, whom from VVD for prime-minister: Bolkestein / Wiegel / Someone else.
n9608: If VVD will be largest party after elections, whom from VVD for prime-minister: Bolkestein / Wiegel / Someone else.
n9615: Who to decide how to govern our country: Bolkestein, Borst, Heerma, de Hoop Scheffer, Jorritsma, Kok, Lubbers, van Mierlo, Rosenmuller, Rottenberg, Sorgdrager, Terpstra, Wallage, Wiegel, Wolffensperger / In two years time new Parliamentary elections: from what parties should there be ministers in Dutch cabinet? / Knowing what parties form government at this time? / Mention parties that form present government / Who to become prime-minister after elections in two years' time?
n9634: Type of people in general speaking truth, being honest teachers, doctors, priests, vicars, TV-newsreaders, professors, judges, 'man or woman in the street', police, survey researchers, civil servants, union-leaders, business-people, politicians, ministers, journalists, scientists (for example natural scientists, chemical scientists, etc.). Reading specific newspapers like: Algemeen Dagblad, De Telegraaf, Het Nieuws van de Dag, NRC Handelsblad, Het Parool, Trouw, De Volkskrant. Reading these newspapers regularly or not.
n9636: Statements about politicians and political parties: Members of Parliament are not concerned with opinions of people like me / At elections political parties only interested in somebody's vote not in one's opinion.
n9638: Placing particular political parties on left-right scale: CDA, PvdA, VVD, D66. Placing particular politicians on left-right scale: Bolkestein, de Boer, Heerma, de Hoop Scheffer, Jorritsma, Kok, Lubbers, van Mierlo, Wallage, Wiegel, Wolffensperger, Weijers.</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr>
            <ddi:nation abbr="NLD" xml:lang="en">The Netherlands</ddi:nation>
            <ddi:collDate event="single">1996</ddi:collDate>
         </ddi:sumDscr>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">OPEN_ACCESS_FOR_REGISTERED_USERS</ddi:restrctn>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: https://dans.knaw.nl/en/about/organisation-and-policy/legal-information/DANSLicence.pdf</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="nl"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>