<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:160005</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:08:07Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>driver</setSpec>
    <setSpec>D30000:D34000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="eng">Text Mining Twelfth-century Perceptions of Factions Dataset</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:parTitl xml:lang="eng">Data for "Is there a Faction in this List?"</ddi:parTitl>
            <ddi:parTitl xml:lang="en">Data for "Is there a Faction in this List?"</ddi:parTitl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-xtf-z3au</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:160005</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en" affiliation="Universiteit Leiden">De Weerdt, Professor H ORCID=0000-0002-9670-674X</ddi:AuthEnty>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="Researcher" affiliation="Universiteit Leiden">Ho, Dr. B., Researcher</ddi:othId>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="Researcher" affiliation="University of California, Berkeley">Wagner, Dr. A, Researcher</ddi:othId>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="RightsHolder" affiliation="Universiteit Leiden">De Weerdt, Professor HILDE ORCID=0000-0002-9670-674X, RightsHolder</ddi:othId>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2020-02-27"/>
         </ddi:distStmt>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="eng">political history; factionalism; Chinese history; digital humanities; medieval history;</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">History</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="eng">This dataset includes all data used in an article comparing the rationale behind twelfth century faction lists. For a fuller description see the original article and the appendix (Is there a Faction in this List? [Hilde De Weerdt, Brent Ho, Allon Wagner, Qiao Jiyan, and Chu Mingkin], Journal of Chinese History 2020).
It includes 
1. the list of names and biographical ids for all those mentioned on the three lists under examination
2.  the raw data extracted from the co-occurrence of these names in corpora including all prose texts authored by authors active at the time when the lists may have been compiled
3. a document describing how the raw data was obtained and curated
4. curated co-occurrence network data for the Yuanyou and Qingyuan lists (differentiating between ties reported in total, in texts excluding self-references by the author, and in texts authored by peers who did not appear on the list)
5. network files including a range of metrics for the Yuanyou and Qingyuan networks
6.  native place and place of office (posting) data for those on the Yuanyou and Qingyuan lists
7. data calculating the significance of particular prefectures and routes in each of these networks
8. an interactive graph showing the significance of particular prefectures and routes in each of these networks
9. data showing sampling results based on the backgrounds of the QIngyuan list
10. raw co-occurrence network data for the sample group
The dataset consists of 34 datafiles and 1 document.
The following researchers helped with curating the data: Wang Wenxin, Daniel Stumm, Liu Jialong, Xiong Hueilan, Monica-Klasing Chen, Zhang Xiaofei, and Gabe van Beijeren, all graduate students at Leiden University.
The research leading to these results has received funding from the European Research Council under the European Union's Seventh Framework Programme (FP7/2007-2013) / ERC grant agreement n° 283525</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr>
            <ddi:collDate event="single">ca. 1080-1220</ddi:collDate>
         </ddi:sumDscr>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:conditions>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="en"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="Chinese"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>