<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:56588</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:07:12Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>driver</setSpec>
    <setSpec>D60000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">NIPO weekpeilingen 1986</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:parTitl xml:lang="en">NIPO opinion polls 1986</ddi:parTitl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:56588</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-xyt-cj77</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">Netherlands Institute for Public Opinion and Marketing Research - NIPO</ddi:AuthEnty>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2014-01-15"/>
         </ddi:distStmt>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">publieke opinie onderzoek</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">opinion poll</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Social sciences</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">Data derived from weekly public opinion polls in the Netherlands in 1986 concerning social and political issues. Samples were drawn from the Dutch population aged 18 years and older.

All data from the surveys held between 1962 and 2000 are available in the DANS data collections.

Background variables:
Sex / age / religion / income / vote recall latest elections / party preference / level of education / union membership / professional status / &lt; self > left-right rating / party alignment / province / degree of urbanization / weight factor.

Topical variables:
n8603: Parliament elections of May 1986 / Preferred political leader Lubbers or Den Uyl / Unemployment among family and friends.
n8604: Peace negotiations between the USA and the USSR / Chance of a nuclear war / Respondent's most important news- and information sources.
n8606: Progress of national economy / Respondent's experience with the progress of economy / Preferred coalition in 1986 / Decrease of unemployment / Feelings about safety at home and in the streets / Preferred coalition with regard to crime prevention / Carnival.
n8607: Position of D66 without Van Mierlo / Alternative choices if political parties as CDA, VVD and PvdA might disappear / Nuclear energy.
n8608: Voting behaviour at local elections / Interest in local politics / Interest in national politics / Influence of local politics on daily life / Preferred influence of the government on local politics / Playing an active roll in local politics / Carnival / St. Valentine's day.
n8609: Knowledge about the political program of the PvdA / Voting decision at the 1986 national elections / Progress of national economy and employment.
n8613: Local elections of 1986 and voting decision / Leadership of VVD, CDA and PvdA / Voting intention at national elections of 1986 / Expectations about the result of the national elections of 1986.
n8614: Local elections of 1986 / Voting intention at parliamentary elections of May 1986 / Voting by proxy / Watching political programs on TV / Listening to political programs on radio / List of political leaders who cause irritation / Way of celebrating Easter.
n8615: Voting intention at parliamentary elections of May 1986 / Party preference / Coalition preference.
n8616: Voting intention at parliamentary elections of May 1986 / Party preference / Coalition preference / Electronic voting / Respondent's opinion about "Centrumpartij" / Attending cinema / Dining out / Having a video player / Renting video movies.
n8617: Voting intention at parliamentary elections of May 1986 / Party preference / Coalition preference / Dutch defense policy / Cruise missiles / Topics of peace movements / NATO.
n8618: Voting intention at parliamentary elections of May 1986 / Party preference / Coalition preference / Respondent's opinion about the Lubbers I administration / Respondent's knowledge about names of ministers in cabinet.
n8619: Voting intention parliamentary elections May 1986 / Party preference / Coalition preference / Demonstrations against "Centrumpartij" / Respondent's opinion about "Centrumpartij" / Respondent's attitude towards the USA.
n8620: Voting intention parliamentary elections May 1986 / Party preference / Coalition preference / Respondent's opinion about the Lubbers I &lt; 1982-1986 > administration concerning the policy towards: unemployment problems, radio, TV, press, education, civil servants, foreign policy, agriculture, national economy, fighting against crime, development aid to third world countries, traffic policy, financial policy, defense policy, environmental policy / Main topics for new cabinet, e.g. health care, social security, euthanasia, shorter working hours, equal treatment of men and women, policy towards foreigners, fighting against drug problems.
n8621: Voting intention at parliamentary elections of May 1986 / Party preference / Coalition preference.
n8622: Voting decision, participation parliamentary elections May 1986 / Electronic voting / Coalition preference / Preferred prime-minister.
n8623: Respondent's opinion about result parliamentary elections May 1986 / Preferred coalition / Preferred prime-minister / Preferred ministers / Leadership CDA, PvdA, VVD, D66.
n8625: Respondent's opinion about making profit by companies, taxes, profit sharing / Respondent's feelings towards the Germans, the English, the Russians, the Americans, the French, the Flemings and the Walloons, the Spanish, the Italians.
n8626: Preferred prime-minister / Unemployment figures / Moonlighting.
n8628: Whether respondent is optimistic or pessimistic / Satisfaction about income / Health / Back pain / Abdominal pain / Headache / Frequency of doctors' treatment.
n8630: Following news about South Africa / Respondent's knowledge about majority groups in South Africa and Zimbabwe / Respondent's opinion about "Apartheid" / Cultural and economic boycott of South Africa / Buying products from South Africa / Having relatives or friends in South Africa.
n8631: Having a driving license or a passport / Sustaining identity papers / Feelings about being registered in several ad- ministrations, computers / Experience with fear of improper use of administrative data / List of occasions of which respondent thinks people are most frightened / List of occasions of which respondent is most frightened / Whether respondent is anxious, optimistic, pessimistic / Expectations about the second term of the Lubbers administration.
n8633: Playing in state lottery, German Lotto, football pools, "Algemene Loterij Nederland", horse races / Gambling in Dutch casino's / Having a set of false teeth / Having a good or a bad set of teeth / Frequency of visiting a dentist.
n8635: If respondent spent his leisure time at the beach whether in The Netherlands or abroad / If respondent did swim in a swimming pool, the sea or open water / If respondent can swim / If respondent took sunbathes, whether in a swimming suit, a bikini, topless or nude / Using sun lotion / If respondent was sailing, rowing, canoeing or sailing in a motorboat, or went for a cruise / Satisfaction about summer holidays / Traffic jams during the summer holidays / Spending holidays with or without children / Preferred family size.
n8637: Upbringing of children / Tax number / Respondents' knowledge of the names of members of the Lubbers II administration.
n8638: Watching the queen's speech &lt; Prinsjesdag > at TV / Respondent's knowledge of names of members of the Lubbers II ad- ministration / Respondent's opinion on birth-control in developing countries / Population development in West-Europe / If Dutch national health service has to refund the anti-conception pill and/or treatment of infertility.
n8639: Government plans and proposed economy measures for 1987.
n8642: Opinion about policies of the Lubbers II administration / Lubbers as prime- minister / The chairmen of the VVD, CDA, PvdA and D66.
n8643: Left-right scaling of PvdA-VVD-CDA / Maximum speed on highways / If respondent accepts trailer camps in his neighbourhood / Which country should be an example for The Netherlands / Which country is supposed to have more prosperity than The Netherlands / Frequency of car driving.
n8645: How far, hashish, prostitution, squatting, nudist beaches, topless, naked men, naked women, having extra marital affairs, homosexuality, sex magazines, are acceptable / Cause of poverty / Whether respondent is introvert or extrovert / Racial discrimination in The Netherlands.
n8647: Preferred role of upper and lower chamber of the Dutch parliament &lt; Eerste Kamer and Tweede Kamer > concerning legislation / Respondent's knowledge about who is voting the upper chamber &lt; Eerste Kamer > of the Dutch parliament / Respondent's knowledge of date of forthcoming elections / Main reason to take part in provincial elections / Voting intention at provincial elections in March 1987 / Which party belongs to political center / Having more or less powerful political convictions.
n8648: Second preferred political party / Opinion about policies of the Lubbers administration / Opinion about prime-minister Lubbers / The chairmen of the VVD, CDA, PvdA and D66.
n8650: Respondent's knowledge about important persons in the field of music, literature, and the art of painting / Frequency of attending a concert, visiting a museum or an exhibition / Frequency of buying, reading books / Frequency of reading novels, short stories or poems / Frequency of attending a play in a theatre / Preference for pop music, popular music, rock music, classical music, jazz / Having interest in the art of painting, music, literature.
n8652: Opinion about policies of cabinet Lubbers, the prime-minister Lubbers / The chairmen of VVD, CDA, PvdA and D66.</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr>
            <ddi:nation abbr="NLD" xml:lang="en">The Netherlands</ddi:nation>
            <ddi:collDate event="single">1986</ddi:collDate>
         </ddi:sumDscr>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">OPEN_ACCESS_FOR_REGISTERED_USERS</ddi:restrctn>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: https://dans.knaw.nl/en/about/organisation-and-policy/legal-information/DANSLicence.pdf</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="nl"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>