<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:33206</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:06:26Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>D60000:D61000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>driver</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">European Values Study 1990, Eastern European Countries - EVS-Eastern Europe'90</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:parTitl xml:lang="en">European Values Study 1990, Eastern European Countries - EVS-Eastern Europe'90</ddi:parTitl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:33206</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-xnz-r6zr</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">Raichev, A., Stoichev, K., n/a * Bulgaria, Koecher, R., Noelle-Neumann, E., n/a * Germany, Titma, M., Saar, A., Klingemann, H.D., n/a * Estonia, Jankiss, E., Manschin, R., n/a * Hungary, Alihaushiene, R., n/a * Lithuania, Janinska-Kania, A., n/a * Poland, Tos, N., n/a * Slovenia, Rehak, J., n/a * Slovakia, Rehak, J., n/a * Czech Republic (primary investigator)</ddi:AuthEnty>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">L.C. Halman, Subfac. Sociale Wetenschappen, Universiteit van Tilburg (depositor)</ddi:AuthEnty>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">National Public Opinion Centre * Sofia, BulgariaInstitut fuer Demoskopie * Allensbach am Bodensee, GermanyMass Communication and Information Center * Tallin, EstoniaGallup Hungary * Budapest, HungaryVilnius State University Sociological Laboratory * Vilnius, LithuaniaOBOP * PolandCenter for Public Opinion Research, University of Ljubljana * Ljubljana, SloveniaInstitute for Social Analysis, Bratislava &amp; Charles University * Bratislava, Slovakia (data collector) </ddi:AuthEnty>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2000-01-01"/>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2007-07-30"/>
         </ddi:distStmt>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">values and beliefs</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">religion</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">family life</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">interpersonal relations</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">social issues</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">living conditions</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">satisfaction</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">employment</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">politics</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">children </ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">philosophy</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Sociology</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">This data collection is designed to enable cross-national comparison of values and beliefs in a wide variety of areas and to monitor changes in values and attitudes of mass publics in European countries. Broad topics covered are work, the meaning and purpose of life, family life, and contemporary social issues. Respondents were asked to rate the importance of work, family, friends, leisure time, politics, and religion in their lives. They were also asked how satisfied they were with their present lives, whether they tended to persuade others close to them, whether they discussed political matters, and how they viewed society. Questions relating to work included what aspects were important to them in a job, the pride they took in their work, their satisfaction with the present job, and their views on owner/state/employee management of business. Respondents were asked about the groups and associations they belonged to and which ones they worked for voluntarily, the level of trust they had in most people, the groups they would not want as neighbours, their general state of health, and whether they felt they had free choice and control over their lives. A wide range of items was included on the meaning and purpose of life, such as respondents' views on the value of scientific advances, the demarcation of good and evil, and religious behaviour and beliefs. Respondents were queried about whether they shared the same attitudes toward religion, morality, politics, and sexual mores with their partner and parents, their views on marriage and divorce, qualities important for a child to learn, whether a child needs both parents to grow up happy, views on mothers working outside the home, views on abortion, and whether marriage is an outdated institution. Questions regarding political issues probed for respondents' opinions of various forms of political action and the likelihood of their taking an action, the most important aims for their countries, confidence in various civil and governmental institutions, and whether they felt divorce, abortion, suicide, cheating on taxes, lying, and other such actions were ever justified Background variables: basic characteristics/ residence/ household characteristics/ occupation/employment/ income/capital assets/ education/ social class/ politics/ religion/ organizational membership</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr>
            <ddi:collDate event="single">1990 * 1992</ddi:collDate>
         </ddi:sumDscr>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">OPEN_ACCESS_FOR_REGISTERED_USERS</ddi:restrctn>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: https://dans.knaw.nl/en/about/organisation-and-policy/legal-information/DANSLicence.pdf</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>