<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:32118</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:05:00Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>D60000:D61000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>driver</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">Aspecten van de levensloop van de Nederlandse bevolking, 1e tranche 1992-1994 : Veranderingen in socio-demografische gegevens, sociale mobiliteit,  relatiegeschiedenis, onderwijsloopbaan en arbeidsmobiliteit.</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:parTitl xml:lang="en">Aspects of life-event history of the Dutch population, part 1, changes in socio-demographic data, social mobility, relationships history, educational career, and work mobility. 1992-1994</ddi:parTitl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:32118</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-xy7-xbj6</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">Stichting Sociaal-culturele Wetenschappen, Nederlandse Organisatie voor Wetenschappelijk onderzoek - NWO * Den Haag (primary investigator)</ddi:AuthEnty>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">Stichting Sociaal-Culturele WetenschappenNederlandse Organisatie voor Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek (research initiator)</ddi:AuthEnty>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">Stichting Telepanel, Amsterdam (data collector)</ddi:AuthEnty>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="1993-01-01"/>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2007-08-10"/>
         </ddi:distStmt>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">living conditions</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">migration</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">social mobility</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">education</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">family life</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">employment</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">occupations</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">interpersonal relations</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Sociology</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">Aspects of life-event history of the Dutch population, part 1: changes in socio-demographic data, social mobility, relationships history, educational career, and work mobility

P1107a: History of address changes / for each address: kind of household, type of housing, duration of stay / reasons for moving / year and month beginning of each new address period / if applicable: if change also meant new school and if for a particular period last child left home. 

P1107b: Respondents recollection of family life with their parents / importance of parents / whether parents divorced / presence other children / parents still alive / education of parents / parents attention to respondents school career. 

P1107c: Characteristics of parents paid job when respondent was ages 12 / if not working what other activities / idem, characteristics of parents paid job now if applicable / if no present job last profession and job situation / all professions CBS coded. 

P1107d: I: Life history of relationships: year and month of event, kind of relationship, reasons for beginning and ending, sex of partner, partner still alive / fourteen possible relationships / if start of living together or marriage, when first engaged and date of birth partner : II: Has respondent had own children, how many, date of birth, adopted and when, date of birth of adopted children/ III: have children died and when / female respondent: pregnant at present, how often pregnant, miscarriage. 

P1107e: Life history of education: pre-school, primary school, and any education following primary. How good a pupil after primary / further education or not / / if university degree and which one / respondent born after 1956, asked of choice of subjects in finishing secondary school / for each training or education: first: year and month of beginning and ending/ second: respondents vocational and job aspiration and succeeded or not and reason for failure / with retrospect respondent is asked for future job desire at age 4 and 12 and at the age of leaving definitively either primary or secondary education. 

P1107f and P1107h: Job history of respondents / any paid job after finished education / kind of work, employer, reason to change to different work / stopped working at all or not and reason / if never joined working force, asked after present situation / per job period at beginning and ending: employed or self-employed, nr. of working hours, net income, nr. of people supervised or employees, changes in nr. of working hours / for each job period profession and place of employment CBS coded. 

P1107g: Most important dates and events from previous questionnaires (P1107a/b/c/d/e/f) presented to respondent for reconsideration and correction / general evaluative questions. 

Background variables: basic characteristics/ place of birth/ residence/ housing situation/ household characteristics/ characteristics of parental family/household/ place of work/ occupation/employment/ income/capital assets/ education/ religion</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr>
            <ddi:collDate event="single">1903 * 1992</ddi:collDate>
         </ddi:sumDscr>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">OPEN_ACCESS_FOR_REGISTERED_USERS</ddi:restrctn>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: https://dans.knaw.nl/en/about/organisation-and-policy/legal-information/DANSLicence.pdf</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>