<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:64516</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-08-31T15:34:49Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>D60000:D61000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">Families of Poles in the Netherlands (FPN) survey. Wave 1.</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-zep-et7y</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:64516</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en" affiliation="Erasmus Universiteit Rotterdam">Karpinska, dr. K. DAI=info:eu-repo/dai/nl/315886382</ddi:AuthEnty>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en" affiliation="Erasmus Universiteit Rotterdam">Dykstra, prof. dr. P.A.</ddi:AuthEnty>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en" affiliation="Nederlands Interdisciplinair Demografisch Instituut (NIDI-KNAW)/ Rijksuniversiteit Groningen; Erasmus Universiteit Rotterdam">Fokkema, dr. T.</ddi:AuthEnty>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="contributor">Funding Agency: European Research Council (324211)</ddi:othId>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2016-04-22"/>
         </ddi:distStmt>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">migration</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">family life</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">Polish migrants</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Social sciences</ddi:topcClas>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Sociology</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">The release of formal restrictions on the free movement of Central and Eastern Europeans that started with the end of the Cold War and the eastward enlargement of the European Union in the 2000s have led to new migration flows in Europe. In the Netherlands, in absolute terms, Poles are the largest group amongst emigrants from the central and eastern European countries which accessed the European Union in 2004. The Families of Poles in the Netherlands (FPN) survey aims to develop a database which allows examining different aspects of Polish migrant family life, including family formation, generational interdependencies, espoused family obligations and life outcomes. 

The sampling frame of the FPN study was population registers (Basisregistratie Personen, BRP). Names and addresses of sample members were drawn by Statistics Netherlands based on the following criteria: the potential respondent was born in Poland, registered in the Netherlands for the first time in 2004 or later, and was between 18 and 49 years old at the time of the most recent registration.  In total 1131 Polish migrants participated in the survey. The fieldwork started in October 2014 and lasted until the end of April 2015.

A blueprint for the survey is the questionnaire of the Generations and Gender Surveys (GGS). The FPN data can be thus matched with the Polish and Dutch GGS, and Onderzoek Gezinsvorming data (OG; a longitudinal data on fertility and family formation executed in the Netherlands) to reveal the impact of contextual and policy influences on, among others, family relationships. 

To study the determinants of family solidarity and migration choices, following changes in respondents’ situations over time is necessary. Therefore, the FPN has a panel character – the second wave of the survey will be repeated in 2017.

The FPN survey was carried out by the Erasmus University Rotterdam and is a part of Pearl Dykstra’s ERC Advanced Investigator project “Families in Context”. Financial support from the European Research Council, Advanced Investigator Grant “Families in Context” (grant agreement no. 324211) is gratefully acknowledged. 

The data from the FPN are accessible via the DANS website to researchers affiliated with academic and (semi-)government organizations. No one has any exclusive right or priority to use the FPN to work on any research question.</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr>
            <ddi:collDate event="single">2014-2015</ddi:collDate>
         </ddi:sumDscr>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">REQUEST_PERMISSION</ddi:restrctn>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: https://dans.knaw.nl/en/about/organisation-and-policy/legal-information/DANSLicence.pdf</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="en"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="Polish"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>