<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:199338</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:08:21Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>driver</setSpec>
    <setSpec>D30000:D33000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>D30000:D34000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">Comparison of the traditions concerning Suraqa's pursuit of the Prophet Muhammad</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:parTitl xml:lang="en">Results of the isnad-cum-matn analysis</ddi:parTitl>
            <ddi:parTitl xml:lang="en">Results of the isnad-cum-matn analysis</ddi:parTitl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-z26-kfse</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:199338</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en" affiliation="Radboud University">Boekhoff-van der Voort, dr. N.A. DAI=info:eu-repo/dai/nl/323841244</ddi:AuthEnty>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt/>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">Islam</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">sira</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">Muhammad</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">miracle story</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">isnad-cum-matn analysis</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Theology and religious studies</ddi:topcClas>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">History</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">This dataset contains the results of my literature study on the traditions relating Surāqa’s pursuit of the Prophet Muḥammad, which allegedly took place during the Hijra, i.e. Muhammad’s flight from Mecca to the town later known as Medina. The traditions, found in Classical Arabic Muslim ḥadīth collections in the field of history, Sīra, Qur'anic exegesis, jurisprudence, among others, have been studied with the isnād-cum-matn analysis. 

The accompanying article “Surāqa’s Pursuit Continues: An Exhaustive Isnād-cum-Matn Analysis of a Miracle Story” is a reply to Andrew Rippin’s criticism on the conclusions from the application of the isnād-cum-matn analysis in one of my earlier articles , in which the analysis has been applied to a small selection of traditions. In “Surāqa’s Pursuit Continues”, I first describe the tradition in question and explain the isnād-cum-matn analysis. Then, the story of Surāqa’s pursuit is thoroughly analyzed by taking into account all available traditions on the story, and finally, the results are compared with the conclusions from my earlier article.

This dataset contains the following documents:

1. “Overview_traditions_in_collections_pursuit_Suraqa”. This document contains the list of where the traditions are found, sorted by hadith collection with mention of the bibliography and the chains of transmission.
2. “Diagram_asanid_traditions_alZuhri”. The diagram with the chains of transmission of all the traditions attributed to the Medinan hadith scholar al-Zuhri (d. 124/742).
3. “Diagram_asanid_traditions_alBara”. The diagram with the chains of transmission of all traditions attributed to Kufan scholar Abu Ishaq Amr b. Abd Allah al-Sabi`i (d. 127/745).
4. “Zuhri-IbnIshaq-comparison” gives an overview of all the differences between the traditions of Ibn Ishaq from al-Zuhri.
5. “Zuhri-Mamar-comparison” gives an overview of all the differences between the traditions of Ma`mar b. Rashid from al-Zuhri.
6. “Zuhri-Uqayl-comparison” gives an overview of all the differences between the traditions of `Uqayl b. Khalid from al-Zuhri.
7. “Zuhri-Musa-comparison” gives an overview of all the differences between the traditions of Musa b. `Uqba from al-Zuhri
8. “Zuhri-students_IbnIshaq-Musa_Salih-comparison” gives an overview of all the differences between the versions of Ibn Ishaq, Musa b. `Uqba and Salih b. Kaysan, all from al-Zuhri.</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr/>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">OPEN_ACCESS_FOR_REGISTERED_USERS</ddi:restrctn>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: https://dans.knaw.nl/en/about/organisation-and-policy/legal-information/DANSLicence.pdf</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="English"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="Arabic"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>