<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:32706</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:06:01Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>D60000:D61000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>driver</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">GPD Survey - The state of the nation 2002</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:parTitl xml:lang="en">GPD enquête - De staat van het land 2002</ddi:parTitl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:32706</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-xuk-32jc</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">Prof.Dr. B.M.S. van Praag, UVA, SEO, J.P. Hop, SEO, Universiteit van Amsterdam (primary investigator)</ddi:AuthEnty>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">Prof. C. Teulings, SEO, Universiteit van Amsterdam (depositor)</ddi:AuthEnty>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2003-12-02"/>
         </ddi:distStmt>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">economics</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Sociology</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">This round of GPD surveys (GPD = Geassocieerde Pers Diensten = Associated Press Services ), a voluntary reply regional newspaper survey, was held in fall 2001 and covers various topics like lifesituation, work and unemployment, housing, environment, time-spending, income and spending, health and political and social opinions.  Themes: children, child care and work, career possibilities / Payed employment: duration, vacation, ADV,  commuting (distance), future expectations regarding unemployment/ Unemployed: duration, pre-unemployment situation, future expectations regarding getting a job, job seeking activities and methods, reasons for non-activity/ Housing situation: age of house, type of house, it's value, choice of location, ownership, expenses, rent, subsidized, size, quality, isolation, garden, balcony, urbanization / Living environment:  annoyances, available facilities and services, safety, victimization, satisfaction with neighbourhood, social contacts /  time budget / detailed data on spending and income, social benefits, debts, job career, flexible working, extra training, pension, evaluation of level of income / Satisfaction / physical situation, health, complaints / family conflicts / freedom, permissiveness / moral standards, values, acquaintance with people breaking laws, punishnment / Politics: voting behaviour, vote intention, memberships labour union / important issues in life / religion / church attendance / place of birth / social contacts with allochtoneous people / satisfaction with national and local institutions and policies / evaluation of political leaders / opinion on multi-cultural society, immigrants, ethnic minorities, integration, international situation, terrorist attacks in US, Islam / lottery, gambling behaviour / life satisfaction in general.   Other background variables include(often both respondent and partner): sex, age, family composition, number of children, education, occupational status, weight, size, handicaps, smoking, drinking, use of drugs,</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr>
            <ddi:collDate event="single">2001</ddi:collDate>
         </ddi:sumDscr>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">OPEN_ACCESS_FOR_REGISTERED_USERS</ddi:restrctn>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: https://dans.knaw.nl/en/about/organisation-and-policy/legal-information/DANSLicence.pdf</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>