<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:68651</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:07:40Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>D30000:D35000:D35400</setSpec>
    <setSpec>driver</setSpec>
    <setSpec>D60000:D66000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">Most popular websites in the Netherlands 2015</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-x6h-6qqt</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:68651</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en" affiliation="Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam">Kleppe, dr. M.</ddi:AuthEnty>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en" affiliation="Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam">Bijleveld, MA H.</ddi:AuthEnty>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt/>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Media sciences</ddi:topcClas>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Communication sciences</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">This dataset contains a list of 3654 Dutch websites that we considered the most popular websites in 2015. This list served as whitelist for the Newstracker Research project in which we monitored the online web behaviour of a group of respondents.

The research project 'The Newstracker' was a subproject of the NWO-funded project 'The New News Consumer: A User-Based Innovation Project to Meet Paradigmatic Change in News Use and Media Habits'. 

For the Newstracker project we aimed to understand the web behaviour of a group of respondents. We created custom-built software to monitor their web browsing behaviour on their laptops and desktops  (please find the code in open access at https://github.com/NITechLabs/NewsTracker). For reasons of scale and privacy we created a whitelist with websites that were the most popular websites in 2015. We manually compiled this list by using data of DDMM, Alexa and own research. The dataset consists of 5 columns:
- the URL
- the type of website: We created a list of types of websites and each website has been manually labeled with 1 category
- Nieuws-regio: When the category was 'News', we subdivided these websites in the regional focus: International, National or Local
- Nieuws-onderwerp: Furthermore, each website under the category News was further subdivided in type of news website. For this we created an own list of news categories and manually coded each website
- Bron: For each website we noted which source we used to find this website.

The full description of the research design of the Newstracker including the set-up of this whitelist is included in the following article: Kleppe, M., Otte, M. (in print), 'Analysing &amp; understanding news consumption patterns by tracking online user behaviour with a multimodal research design', Digital Scholarship in the Humanities, doi 10.1093/llc/fqx030.</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr/>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="nl"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>