<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:61753</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:07:24Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>driver</setSpec>
    <setSpec>D60000:D64000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">Push and Pull Factors of International Migration</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-xnk-b4k4</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:61753</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en" affiliation="Netherlands Interdisciplinary Demographic Institute (NIDI)">Groenewold, Drs. W.G.F.</ddi:AuthEnty>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="contributor">Eurostat</ddi:othId>
            <ddi:othId xml:lang="en" role="contributor">Funding Agency: European Commission</ddi:othId>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2015-07-21"/>
         </ddi:distStmt>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">international migration</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">push and pull factors</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">survey</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">housholds</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">indiviuals</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Demography</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">General purpose multi-country survey project collecting data on push and pull factors of international migration in selected origin and destination countries. Project was funded by the European Commission, executed by Eurostat and implemented by NIDI in collaboration and consultation with country teams in Ghana, Morocco, Senegal, Egypt, Turkey, Italy, Spain. Both households with and without emigrated or returned households members were sampled and interviewed between 1996-1998 in these countries.  In origin countries households were sampled. In destination countries individual respondents were sampled.

Before using the data, read the methodology section and technical appendix of the Comparative Research Report. Analyze the data using country-specific questionnaires, and consult country-specific research reports about design, implementation, and analytical results regarding push and pull factors of migration. Country reports and the comparative report follow the same structure. 

Consult the enumerator-instruction manual to familiarize with concepts and -definitions that are specific to this international migration survey project.  For each country, there are always two main data-files available: one household-level file and one so-called join-match file. The former file only comprises characteristics of the household, the latter comprises individual-respondent characteristics as well as all characteristics of the household to which a respondent belongs. Data file variable names correspond with questionnaire numbers.  Data file variable and value labels correspond with numbers and answer categories in the questionnaires. Code 9,99,999, etc. is missing value, 8,98,998 is don't know, 7, 97,997 is refuse to answer question. SPSS system missing code (.) is used in case a question is not applicable to respondent. Standardized weights are included in files.

Additional files have been added comprising specific information about particular country-data files.</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr>
            <ddi:collDate event="single">1996-1998</ddi:collDate>
         </ddi:sumDscr>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">OPEN_ACCESS_FOR_REGISTERED_USERS</ddi:restrctn>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: https://dans.knaw.nl/en/about/organisation-and-policy/legal-information/DANSLicence.pdf</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="en"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="fr"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>