<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:56758</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:07:12Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>driver</setSpec>
    <setSpec>D60000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">NIPO weekpeilingen 1993</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:parTitl xml:lang="en">NIPO opinion polls 1993</ddi:parTitl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:56758</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-x33-qdy8</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">Netherlands Institute for Public Opinion and Marketing Research - NIPO</ddi:AuthEnty>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2014-01-21"/>
         </ddi:distStmt>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">publieke opinie onderzoek</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">opinion poll</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Social sciences</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">Data derived from weekly public opinion polls in the Netherlands in 1993 concerning social and political issues. Samples were drawn from the Dutch population aged 18 years and older.

All data from the surveys held between 1962 and 2000 are available in the DANS data collections.

Background variables:
Sex / age / religion / income / vote recall latest elections / party preference / level of education / union membership / professional status / &lt; self > left-right rating / party alignment / province / degree of urbanization / weight factor.

Topical variables:
n9312: Respondent's familiarity with individualization of society / Whether respondent considers himself as a member of a family, member of a union, member of a church, member of an occupational group, active member of one or more clubs, societies or pressure group, member of a political party, or specific political conviction / Feelings concerning: belonging to a certain region, city, village or province, the feeling being Dutch / Respondent's on togetherness / Preferred political administrator / Desired political influence of: d'Ancona, Bolkestein, Brinkman, Dales, van Dam, Kok, Kooijmans, Lubbers, May-Weggen, van Mierlo, Rottenberg, Wiegel, Wöltgens, Zijlstra.
n9317: Whether respondent visited foreign countries, for holidays or for work / Whether respondent visited: Belgium, Germany, France, Great Britain, Spain, Italy, Portugal, Austria, Switzerland, Greece, USA, Indonesia / Whether respondent got to know one or more inhabitants of those countries / Attitude towards inhabitants of Belgium, France, Germany, Great Britain and the USA / Qualities of the Belgians, the French, the Germans, the British, the Americans, and the Dutch in the field of hard working, enjoying life, reliable, good for having fun, making products of very good quality, having no sense of humour, being polite, dictatorially or ambitious, good clients who like to buy Dutch products, vain or conceited, democratic, enjoyable.
n9318: Preferred denomination of mayors, by citizens, by the city council or by the home secretary / If respondent could vote for the prime-minister, which of the following persons should respondent choose: Ria Beckers, Bolkestein, Brinkman, Marcel van Dam, Wim Kok, Lubbers, Van Mierlo, De Vries, Wiegel, Wöltgens.
n9323: Respondent’s opinion about the present coalition / Voting intention at the coming parliamentary elections / Preferred coalition after the coming parliamentary elections / Whether the political party 'Groen Links' [environmentalists] should also be a partner in the next coalition / Whether respondent is personally involved in the proposed government program concerning: a professional army, the 'Betuwe' railroad line, disability benefits, changes in social security payments for persons between 18 and 21 years old, changes in the medical insurance system, the salaries of civil servants / Consequences for respondents income.
n9325: Whether respondent knows in which city the headquarters of the European Community is having residence / Respondents interest in the European Community / Whether one of the following countries, all members of the European Community, should be excluded from membership: Belgium, Denmark, Germany, Great Britain, France, Greece, Ireland, Italy, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, Portugal, Spain / Whether one of the following countries, all non-members of the European Community, should be included in the EC member- ship: Finland, Hungary, Norway, Austria, Poland, Czechia, Turkey, Sweden, Switzerland / Whether respondent feels more affinity with the Christian, the socialist or the liberal movements in Dutch politics / Whether respondent knows which political parties belong to the socialist movement.
n9330: Respondent identifies him/Herself with one of three political mainstreams: Christian, Socialist, Liberal. To what political mainstream does Van Mierlo, Brinkman, Bolkestein belong? Which political parties define as liberal. Some basic facilities like housing, work, medical care, education task of government or of people themselves.
n9331: Voting intention for Parliamentary elections may 1994. When voting: voting for a particular party or against one or more particular parties. Voting for particular party because oppose particular person from another party. Voting for particular party because of a particular person. If elections for prime-minister, respondent would choose Brinkman/Wiegel, Kok/Van Mierlo, Brinkman/Wiegel, Van Mierlo/Wiegel of two candidates.
n9333: Respondent might vote for one or more political parties in future. Ever voted for one of all political parties that existed in last decade. What is the ideal family size. Population in the Netherlands increases by immigrants and those who ask for asylum: good or bad development. Precautions necessary to restrict number of immigrants. Immigrants will assimilate in the long end, will learn our language, etc. Children and grandchildren of immigrants will be Dutch?
n9335: Impact of problem of unemployment for our country. Judgment of government policy on unemployment. In abandoning minimum wages will their be more people getting work? Would abandoning minimum wages be good or bad for Dutch economy? Own income would be effected Own opinion on abandoning minimum wages. Dutch politics has three political mainstreams: Christian, Socialist, Liberal: respondents' own identification / What political mainstream best for Dutch economy / Best for un/employment policy / Best for those who receive social security benefits.
n9337: Respondent is driving a car or motorcycle. Number of kilometers driving per year. Using gas gasoline or LPG. Because of increase in taxes on gas respondent will drive less kilometers. Respondent will look for alternatives like public transport, car-pooling, bicycle. Tax increase on gas justifiable.
n9339: Respondent followed opening Parliament directly via television or radio. If not, saw, heard or read parts of opening at other time. Government plans as presented clear enough. In what way will government plans effect economy / Effect on employment situation / Effect on social security benefits / Respondent self will be better or worse off. Retrenchment policy of government necessary or not. Opinion on degree of retrenchment. Opinion on government plans in general. Trust in government after presentation of plans. Preferred coalition in government after Parliamentary elections in may 1994.
n9342: Took knowledge of one or more already published party programs / Idea of what parties want to happen in the Netherlands in particularly: PvdA - D66 - CDA - VVD - Groen Links / Statements about political parties: PvdA - VVD =3D D66 - CDA : always voted for / Old fashioned, not of this time / Has to be in next government / Is a Christian party / Has good party leader / Is a socialist party / practical, good plans / Is a liberal party / Best programme for Dutch economy / Is really progressive / Best programme for my interest and income / Best programme for social security benefits.
n9346: Would vote for party leader of particular party / When voting, vote particular person or just a party / If Lubbers on list of candidates, would vote for him / If Van Agt, Wiegel, Terlouw on list of candidates, would vote for him / Likely that names of persons involved in crime will appear on candidates lists.
n9348: Expectations in 1994 for oneself / Expectations in 1994 for more or less strikes, labour conflicts / Expectations in 1994 for more or less international conflicts / Scale concerning expectations world war within next ten years.
n9349: Will vote in 1994 for local or national party at municipal elections / Satisfied with big political parties / Will possibly vote for other party than usually as a means of protest / Will vote &lt; to protest > for particular party / Representatives act according to will of voters or not / Voting behaviour in general / Always voted or stayed home / Will vote at municipal elections march 1994 / Will vote at parliamentary elections in may 1994.</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr>
            <ddi:nation abbr="NLD" xml:lang="en">The Netherlands</ddi:nation>
            <ddi:collDate event="single">1993</ddi:collDate>
         </ddi:sumDscr>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">OPEN_ACCESS_FOR_REGISTERED_USERS</ddi:restrctn>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: https://dans.knaw.nl/en/about/organisation-and-policy/legal-information/DANSLicence.pdf</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="nl"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>