<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:56512</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:07:11Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>driver</setSpec>
    <setSpec>D60000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">NIPO weekpeilingen 1978</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:parTitl xml:lang="en">NIPO opinion polls 1978</ddi:parTitl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:56512</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-zxp-jnw6</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">Netherlands Institute for Public Opinion and Marketing Research - NIPO</ddi:AuthEnty>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2014-01-08"/>
         </ddi:distStmt>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">publieke opinie onderzoek</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">opinion poll</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Social sciences</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">Data derived from weekly public opinion polls in the Netherlands in 1978 concerning social and political issues. Samples were drawn from the Dutch population aged 18 years and older.

All data from the surveys held between 1962 and 2000 are available in the DANS data collections.

Background variables:
Sex / age / religion / income / vote recall latest elections / party preference / level of education / union membership / professional status / &lt; self > left-right rating / party alignment / province / degree of urbanization / weight factor.

Topical variables:
n7802: Expected term of present administration / Relationship between trade unions and administration.
n7803: Awareness of forthcoming elections / Party preference.
n7804: Preferred political party within CDA, or preference for CDA itself / Voting intention forthcoming elections and expectations of results / Difference between PvdA and D66.
n7806: Confidence in cabinet and leading politicians / Whether present administration is leftwing or rightwing / Export of Dutch uranium to Brazil / Nuclear plant at Almelo, maintenance, expansion or closure.
n7807: Dutch participation in world championship football in Argentina / Ideal family size and overpopulation / Influenza and common cold / Smoking behaviour.
n7808: Tax evasion by politicians / filling out of the Income tax form / Whether pay slip is clear / Attitude towards tax evasion.
n7811: Skating and skiing / Air and water pollution / The government's concern with "people like us".
n7813: unusable &lt; multi-punches >.
n7814: Belief in life after death, heaven and hell, God / Being a Christian, an atheist or a humanist / Neutron bomb / Military counterbalance towards the Soviet Union and the Communist Countries / Cuban military aid for African countries like Angola and Ethiopia.
n7815: Priorities of new administration , concerning unemployment, inflation, abortion, works councils, profit sharing act &lt; Vermogensaanwasdeling VAD >, income policy / Wage earners' type of employment.
n7816: Number of children in the family / Whether children were planned / Ideal family size / Presence of father during childbirth.
n7817: Confidence in cabinet and leading politicians / Hypothetical choices between interests of the Netherlands versus interests of foreign countries / Preserving natural landscape versus increasing agricultural production / Strong central leadership versus citizen participation / More factories versus less employment and lower wages / Friendly relations with colleagues versus promotion / Technical progress versus human values.
n7818: Influence of radio and television on political party preference / Whether radio and TV reflect viewpoints of political parties accurately / Whether cabinet and parliament represent viewpoints of VVD, CDA, PvdA, trade unions, employers, average citizen.
n7819: Frequency of having a flu / Smoking behaviour.
n7820: Whitsuntide and Ascension Day holiday trips and having problems with traffic jams / Traffic congestion in general / Type of transportation to and from work.
n7822: Having a Bible and reading the Bible / Whether the message in the Bible still should be taken seriously / Whether the lessons of Thorbecke, Willem van Oranje, Abraham Kuyper, Karl Marx, Lenin, Churchill, and the Pope still should be taken seriously.
n7823: Which current affairs program on TV respondent is watching: KRO-Brandpunt, NCRV-Hier-en-Nu, Tros-Aktua, Avro-Televizier, Vara-Visie, NOS-Den-Haag-Vandaag and whether they give reliable information or are making propaganda.
n7825: Awareness of planned strikes in public sector / Personally being troubled by strikes / Whether civil servants should strike, like government and city personnel, public transport personnel, personnel of the public electrical service, PTT personnel, fire brigade, and railroad personnel / Whether wage earner is working in public sector.
n7827: Awareness of planned strikes in public sector / Personally being troubled by strikes / Whether wage earner is working in public sector / Whether employees in public sector should have the right to strike / Salary and pension advantages of civil servants.
n7834: Prayer restored in Queen's Annual Speech / Travelling during summer holiday outside The Netherlands / Mode of transportation / Problems with traffic jams.
n7835: Export of Shell oil to Rhodesia and whether the government should investigate this matter / Objection to violations of United Nations &lt; UNO > sanctions against Rhodesia / Extent of trust in foreign countries like West-Germany, the USSR, and the USA / Confidence in present administration / Whether the administration is leftwing or rightwing.
n7837: Urgency of tasks and problems facing government like unemployment, inflation, crime, abuse of social services, the profit sharing proposal &lt; Vermogensaanwasdeling VAD >, abortion legislation, stimulating business and industry via investment, raising corporate profits, wage and price control / Satisfaction with income.
n7839: Did Queen's Annual Speech and national budget affect confidence in cabinet / Expected effect of government programs for general economy, unemployment, welfare of average citizen / Daylight saving time.
n7840: Urgency of tasks and problems facing government like unemployment, inflation, crime, abuse of social services, the VAD &lt; profit sharing proposal >, abortion legislation, stimulating business and industry via investment, raising corporate profits, wage and price control / Satisfaction with income.
n7843: Confidence in leading politicians, police force, elementary school system, vocational school system, trade unions, armed forces, judicial system, banks, churches.
n7844: Deportation of members of the West-German "Rote Armee Fraktion" &lt; RAF > / Membership of Parliament of ex-ministers Van der Stoel, Van Kemenade, Den Uyl and Van Dam / Resignation of minister Boersma.
n7845: Forthcoming collective bargaining / Social security benefits and relation to purchasing power / Inflation and income policy / Having a job on the side.
n7848: Parents' legal responsibility for children and controversy about adulthood / Resignation of Aantjes as a member of Parliament, in conjunction with his political sympathies before World War II.
n7849: Attitude towards changes in society concerning: sexual freedom, the authorities, working hard, earning money, technical progress, family life, soft drugs, leisure activities, large families, working women, education / Usefulness of public opinion polls for the government, industry, media, and average citizen.
n7851: Price compensation or higher wages / Satisfaction with income / Civil service salaries and pensions better or worse than in business and industry / Strikes in public sector / Government and trade unions obstruct one another or cooperate / Wage earner working in public sector / Prosecution of war criminal Menten.</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr>
            <ddi:nation abbr="NLD" xml:lang="en">The Netherlands</ddi:nation>
            <ddi:collDate event="single">1978</ddi:collDate>
         </ddi:sumDscr>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">OPEN_ACCESS_FOR_REGISTERED_USERS</ddi:restrctn>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: https://dans.knaw.nl/en/about/organisation-and-policy/legal-information/DANSLicence.pdf</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="nl"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>