<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><record xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/">
  <header>
    <identifier>oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:56514</identifier>
    <datestamp>2021-04-15T21:07:11Z</datestamp>
    <setSpec>driver</setSpec>
    <setSpec>D60000</setSpec>
    <setSpec>easy-collection:7</setSpec>
  </header>
  <metadata>
<ddi:codeBook xmlns:ddi="ddi:codebook:2_5" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xsi:schemaLocation="ddi:codebook:2_5 http://www.ddialliance.org/Specification/DDI-Codebook/2.5/XMLSchema/codebook.xsd" version="2.5" xml:lang="en">
   <ddi:docDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl/>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:prodStmt>
            <ddi:producer xml:lang="en">DANS-KNAW</ddi:producer>
         </ddi:prodStmt>
         <ddi:holdings xml:lang="en" URI="http://easy.dans.knaw.nl"/>
      </ddi:citation>
   </ddi:docDscr>
   <ddi:stdyDscr>
      <ddi:citation>
         <ddi:titlStmt>
            <ddi:titl xml:lang="en">NIPO weekpeilingen 1979</ddi:titl>
            <ddi:parTitl xml:lang="en">NIPO opinion polls 1979</ddi:parTitl>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DANS-KNAW">oai:easy.dans.knaw.nl:easy-dataset:56514</ddi:IDNo>
            <ddi:IDNo agency="DOI">https://doi.org/10.17026/dans-zjz-cyz6</ddi:IDNo>
         </ddi:titlStmt>
         <ddi:rspStmt>
            <ddi:AuthEnty xml:lang="en">Netherlands Institute for Public Opinion and Marketing Research - NIPO</ddi:AuthEnty>
         </ddi:rspStmt>
         <ddi:distStmt>
            <ddi:distDate xml:lang="en" date="2014-01-08"/>
         </ddi:distStmt>
      </ddi:citation>
      <ddi:stdyInfo>
         <ddi:subject>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">publieke opinie onderzoek</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:keyword xml:lang="en">opinion poll</ddi:keyword>
            <ddi:topcClas xml:lang="en" vocab="NARCIS-classification" vocabURI="http://www.narcis.nl/classification">Social sciences</ddi:topcClas>
         </ddi:subject>
         <ddi:abstract xml:lang="en">Data derived from weekly public opinion polls in the Netherlands in 1979 concerning social and political issues. Samples were drawn from the Dutch population aged 18 years and older.

All data from the surveys held between 1962 and 2000 are available in the DANS data collections.

Background variables:
Sex / age / religion / income / vote recall latest elections / party preference / level of education / union membership / professional status / &lt; self > left-right rating / party alignment / province / degree of urbanization / weight factor.

Topical variables:
n7902: Knowledge of salary for next year / Satisfaction with income / Living a good life / What about lower income / Firmness in religion / Political conviction / Confidence in present ad- ministration.
n7903: Confidence in ministers, members of parliament, leaders of parliamentary parties.
n7904: European elections: knowledge of forthcoming elections, voting intention and party preference, knowledge of PvdA party leader, preference for Mrs. v.d. Heuvel or Mr. Vondeling as PvdA party leader / Independence of Dutch Antilles / Proposed income policy by the FNV union and its influences on the Dutch economy and unemployment / Strikes as possible means to enforce the FNV income policy proposals.
n7905: Admission to hospital / Paying Hfl. 5 per night during hospitalization / Kind of medical insurance / Dutch soldiers in Lebanon on request of the United Nations Organizations &lt; UNO >.
n7906: Appreciation of the present cold wintry weather, and its possible negative consequences for respondent.
n7909: Appreciation of the cold wintry weather, and its possible negative consequence for respondent / Shirt advertising by foot- ball players / New law concerning abortion.
n7911: Influence of European election on Dutch political situation / Whether party preference at European elections is determined by European or Dutch problems / Having a car, use of car and percentage of income which is spent at use of a car / Whether respondent's house is owned or rented, and percentage of income which is spent at mortgage or rent.
n7912: Solidarity with KVP, ARP, CHU or CDA / Formation of the CDA / Future and current political position of CDA / Confidence in CDA politicians &lt; former ARP-politicians >.
n7913: Influence of Dutch results at European elections on internal Dutch affairs / Voting at European elections influenced by internal or European problems / Building nuclear plants in the Nether- lands / Energy saving within European Community / Peace negotiations between Israel and Egypt.
n7915: Influence of Dutch results at European elections on internal Dutch affairs / Voting at European elections influenced by internal or European problems / Working outdoors or indoors / Arrival time at home after work / Time of finishing dinner / Time of going to bed on working days / Summer holidays.
n7916: Law and order in society / Participation in society / Church and religion in society / Importance trade and industry in society / Abiding to rules and laws in society / Making lot of money if dedication great / Authority and discipline in society / Possibilities to develop a perfect society.
n7917: Influence of Dutch results at European elections on internal Dutch affairs / Voting at European elections influenced by internal or by European problems / Building nuclear plants in Holland / Number of nuclear plants in Holland / Comparison of risks at working in a coal-mine or working in a nuclear plant / Comparison of rate of pollution caused by coal-mines or nuclear plants / Security control in Dutch nuclear plants / The need to close nuclear plants / Membership of Mr. Aantjes, party leader of CDA, of the German SS during the second World War.
n7918: Education period and whether respondent finished his/her education untimely / Having children / Ability to handle children / Managerial and leadership qualities / Being decisive / Attitude towards consultation in organizations.
n7919: Influence of Dutch results at European elections on Dutch internal affairs / Voting at European elections influenced by internal or by European problems / Acquaintance with new leader of PvdA / Preferred PvdA leader / Political influence of PvdA chairman / Current political position of PvdA / Confidence in PvdA / Confidence in the Van Agt administration.
n7920: Building more nuclear plants in the Netherlands / Necessity to close all nuclear plants / Necessity to close the uranium factory at Almelo / Recent PvdA congress and its proposals concerning nuclear energy, and reduction of working hours.
n7921: Influence of Dutch results at European elections on internal Dutch affairs / Voting at European elections influenced by internal or by European problems / Having a black-and-white or colour TV / Having a radio / Preferred broadcasting company / Subscription to TV radio magazine / Being a member on reduced subscription &lt; "Tientjeslid" > / Distribution of broadcasting time / Preference for CDA-VVD or CDA-PvdA coalition.
n7922: Use of moonlighters and paying of value added tax &lt; BTW > / Having a rowing-boat, sailing boat, motorboat, a berth and or a trailer / Having of a caravan / Having a stand, garage, parking place for caravan / Having a second house, and in which country.
n7923: Activities during Whitsuntide weekend / Traffic jams during Whitsuntide weekend.
n7924: Income compared with last year / Satisfaction with income / Reduction of WAO and WW benefits / Chance to get unemployed or to get unable to work / Index linking versus salary increase.
n7929: Leisure activities / Having a swimming suit / Swimming pools.
n7930: Developments in the Netherlands concerning: inflation, unemployment, costs of living, relation between unions and employers, relation government unions, energy supply, quality of goods, working conditions, ecology, quality of education, quality of public transport, security on the street, financial security after retirement, discipline and order, housing / Income of respondent, future of respondent.
n7931: Energy shortage / Nuclear plants in the Netherlands / Uranium factory at Almelo / Solar energy in the Netherlands / The winning of gas and oil in scenic areas / Renting or owning a house / Thermic isolation of houses / Paying value-added tax &lt; BTW > on bills.
n7932: Publicity of incomes, privacy aspects / Minimum and maximum wages / Maximum wages for sportsmen, artists / Possibility to restrict high incomes / Being jealous of people who earn more money / Importance and urgency of government tasks: profit sharing &lt; Vermogensaanwasdeling VAD >, &lt; abuse > of social benefits, economic and income policy, abortion, military expenses, building nuclear plants, restricting energy use, policy towards crime, to promote cooperation between unions and employees.
n7937: &lt; Solidarity with > strikes in the harbour of Rotterdam / Participation in unofficial strikes and strikes organized by unions / Confidence in unions &lt; FNV and CNV > / Confidence in management of organization where respondent or respondent's partner is working / Satisfaction with income / Index linking instead of salary increase.
n7938: Opening of Parliamentary Year / The Queen's speech &lt; Troonrede > and the budget &lt; Miljoenennota > / Confidence in present administration / Nuclear arms policy of the United States of America
n7942: Strikes at SHELL, Pernis &lt; - > Rotterdam / Confidence in unions &lt; FNV and CNV > / Confidence in management of organization where respondent or respondent's husband is working / NATO and Warsaw Pact / Nuclear armament of both organizations / Presence of middle distance nuclear weapons in the Netherlands / Necessity of military counterbalance between West-Europe and the USSR / Dutch NATO membership / Disarmament policy / Confidence in promises concerning disarmament policy of the USSR and other East-European countries / Disarmament proposals of the IKV &lt; Interkerkelijk Vredesberaad > / Preferred armament policy in West-Europe.
n7944: Anti-Semitism in the Netherlands / Attitude towards PLO &lt; Palestinian Liberation Organization > and Israel / Opinion about the Pope and its travels / Attending hotels, restaurants and cafe's and respondent's opinion about their service / Future energy supply by nuclear power stations / Pollution by burning of coal in generating stations.
n7945: Use of military means / Expectations for 1980 concerning: prices, employment, labour conflicts, taxes, economic situation, peace, power of the USA and the USSR, income policy / Celebrating Sinterklaas and Christmas.
n7946: Left-right scaling of political parties / Foundation of the "Sociale Centrum Partij" and voting intention at this political party.
n7947: Possession of durables and assessment of their dispensability / Regularly going on holidays and dispensability of holidays / Dispensability of daily work / Dispensability of membership of clubs / Assessment of own happiness.
n7949: Having a black-and-white or colour TV / Community aerial / Cable television / Watching foreign TV channels / TV advertising / Most sympathetic broadcasting companies.
n7950: Change in attitude towards D66, VVD, PvdA, CDA / Most important politician in 1980 / Income expectations for 1980 / Satisfaction with income / Assessment of own happiness.
n7951: Participation in demonstrations, actions and meetings / Preference for a second term of the Den Uyl administration / Preferred next coalition.</ddi:abstract>
         <ddi:sumDscr>
            <ddi:nation abbr="NLD" xml:lang="en">The Netherlands</ddi:nation>
            <ddi:collDate event="single">1979</ddi:collDate>
         </ddi:sumDscr>
      </ddi:stdyInfo>
      <ddi:dataAccs>
         <ddi:useStmt>
            <ddi:restrctn xml:lang="en">OPEN_ACCESS_FOR_REGISTERED_USERS</ddi:restrctn>
            <ddi:conditions xml:lang="en">License: https://dans.knaw.nl/en/about/organisation-and-policy/legal-information/DANSLicence.pdf</ddi:conditions>
         </ddi:useStmt>
      </ddi:dataAccs>
   </ddi:stdyDscr>
   <ddi:fileDscr>
      <ddi:fileTxt xml:lang="nl"/>
   </ddi:fileDscr>
</ddi:codeBook>
  </metadata>
</record>